

GEOSPATIAL SCIENTIST

Details

Enschede Netherlands +31647724738 mutugichris@gmail.com

Links

Github

LinkedIn

Skills

GIS

Remote sensing

Git

SQL

Python and R

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

Profile

An organised, meticulous and adaptable geospatial scientist with experience studying and working with Geographic Information Systems (GIS) and remote sensing technologies. A technology enthusiast keen to learn, solve problems and improve processes or facilitate their digital transformation through industry-leading technologies.

Employment History

Artificial Intelligence Research Intern, Estonian Land Board, Tartu

MAY 2022 - JUNE 2022

 Delivered the first phase of testing deep learning capability in detecting buildings' footprints as a possible way of updating the board's topographical datasets

Geospatial data analyst, Konza Silicon, Nairobi, Kenya.

NOVEMBER 2019 - JULY 2021

- Analysed cadastral data to explore, understand trends, and automate land transaction workflows for Kenya's Land information management system (LIMS).
- Developed and recommended land data and metadata digitisation procedures consistent with company objectives for the launched Kenyan LIMS.
- Worked as the Geographic Information Systems (GIS) team lead and conducted training for team members and other stakeholders on the LIMS.

GIS and remote sensing intern, Lentera Africa, Kiambu, Kenya.

SEPTEMBER 2019 - OCTOBER 2019

- Initialised the company's GIS department for the collection and harmonisation
 of farm information, such as field attributes yield data and farm boundaries,
 through field visits and GIS-based techniques
- Processed and analysed remotely sensed data for crop and soil management to provide sufficient crop health information to farmers.

Education

MSc in Geo-information Science and Earth Observation for Environmental Modelling and Management for Urban-Rural Interactions, University of Twente, Enschede, Netherlands.

AUGUST 2022 - PRESENT

Thesis topic: Inter-comparison of methods for estimating leaf angle distribution with LiDAR data for broad-leaf tree species.

MSc in Geo-informatics for urbanised societies, University of Tartu, Tartu, Estonia.

AUGUST 2021 - AUGUST 2022

Weighted Average Grade: 4.81/5

BSc in Geospatial Engineering, University of Nairobi, Nairobi, Kenya.

JANUARY 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Thesis topic: Application of GIS in locating suitable sites for solar photovoltaic farms: A case study of Kajiado County, Kenya.